<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Bulgaria Tour Guide</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="nav_header_title">Bulgaria</string>
    <string name="nav_header_subtitle">The Silicon Valley of Europe</string>
    <string name="nav_header_desc">Navigation header</string>

    <string name="action_bulgaria">Bulgaria</string>
    <string name="action_city_one">Sofia</string>
    <string name="action_city_two">Varna</string>
    <string name="action_city_three">Burgas</string>
    <string name="action_city_four">Plovdiv</string>
    <string name="action_about">About the app</string>

    <string name="skip">SKIP</string>

    <string name="category_first">Culture</string>
    <string name="category_second">Nightlife</string>
    <string name="category_third">History</string>
    <string name="category_fourth">Attractions</string>

    <string name="city_one">Sofia</string>
    <string name="city_two">Varna</string>
    <string name="city_three">Burgas</string>
    <string name="city_four">Plovdiv</string>

    <string name="bulgaria">BULGARIA</string>
    <string name="bulgarian_saying">When God gave the peoples of the world their lands, He had forgotten about the Bulgarians, and because there was no land left for them, He tore a piece of Heaven for them. - a Bulgarian saying.</string>

    <string name="about_bulgaria">Bulgaria, officially the Republic of Bulgaria is a country in the Balkans, west of the Black Sea. It borders Romania to the north, Serbia to the northwest, the Republic of Macedonia to the southwest, Greece to the south, and Turkey to the southeast.\n\nBeing located close to the Turkish Straits means the key land routes from Europe to the Middle East and Asia pass through Bulgaria. Thanks to this location, the territory of the country has been of interest to many peoples that have left their impact on the land. Remains of various civilizations and epochs are scattered all across the country and can still be seen today. From the tombs of the mighty Thracian kings, through the theatres of the ancient Greeks and the stadiums of the Roman Empire, to the medieval castles of the kings of the First and Second Bulgarian Empire, and the mosques from the Ottoman rule.\n\nPresent-day Bulgaria is one of the few remaining exotic destinations of Europe, because it boasts sublime beaches on its seaside, lovely churches and winter sport opportunities in its mountains, as well as a unique architectural ensemble of modern, classic and ethical styles in each of its cities and towns, to name a few. Although it is not as well travelled as other countries in Europe, it is a beautiful place, with a wide range of activities for the traveller to do. Despite not being a large country (approximately the size of Cuba, Portugal or the state of Virginia), Bulgaria offers a wide diversity of landscapes, each possessing its own unique beauty. Because of its natural diversity there is a great number of tourism opportunities in the country.\n\nThere is a wide variety of historical, natural, religious and artistic sights to see in Bulgaria. All across the country there are remains of different epochs and eras, societies and peoples, spiritual and artistic personae that create a beautiful mix of ethnic culture full of unique traditions and rituals combined with a sense of belonging to the movements that have shaped the world as we know it today. The Bulgarian tourist movement, established more than one hundred years ago, has promoted the acknowledgement of all the sights that form the distinguished Bulgarian identity through its so called "100 Tourist Sites of Bulgaria" program that covers most of Bulgaria\'s must-see attractions. Of course, nowadays the program includes more than two hundred and fifty one-of-a-kind places of interest but the name still remains.</string>
    <string name="about_city_one">Sofia is the capital and largest city of Bulgaria. 1.3 million people live in the city and 1.7 million people live in its metropolitan area. The city is at the foot of Vitosha Mountain in the western part of the country. Being in the centre of the Balkan peninsula, it is midway between the Black Sea and the Adriatic Sea, and closest to the Aegean Sea.\n\nSofia has been an area of human habitation since at least 7000 BC. Being Bulgaria\'s primate city, Sofia is a hometown of many of the major local universities, cultural institutions and commercial companies. Sofia is one of the top 10 best places for start-up business in the world, especially in information technologies. Sofia was Europe\'s most affordable capital to visit in 2013.\n\nSofia is one of the most visited tourist destinations in Bulgaria alongside coastal and mountain resorts. Among its highlights is the Alexander Nevsky Cathedral, one of the symbols of Bulgaria, constructed in the late 19th century. It occupies an area of 3,170 square metres (34,122 square feet) and can hold 10,000 people.\n\nSofia holds Bulgaria\'s largest museum collections, which attract tourists and students for practical studies. The National Historical Museum in Boyana district has a vast collection of more than 650,000 historical items dating from Prehistory to the modern era, although only 10,000 of them are permanently displayed due to the lack of space. Smaller collections of items related mostly to the history of Sofia are in the National Archaeological Museum, a former mosque located between the edifices of the National Bank and the Presidency. Two natural sciences museums — the Natural History Museum and the Earth and Man — display minerals, animal species (alive and taxidermic) and rare materials. The Ethnographic Museum and the National Museum of Military History are other places of interest, holding large collections of Bulgarian folk costumes and armaments, respectively.\n\nVitosha Boulevard, also called Vitoshka, is a pedestrian zone with numerous cafés, restaurants, fashion boutiques, and luxury goods stores. Sofia\'s geographic location, in the foothills of the weekend retreat Vitosha mountain, further adds to the city\'s specific atmosphere.</string>
    <string name="about_city_two">Varna is the third largest city in Bulgaria and the largest city and seaside resort on the Bulgarian Black Sea Coast. Situated strategically in the Gulf of Varna, the city has been a major economic, social and cultural centre for almost three millennia. Varna, historically known as Odessos, grew from a Thracian seaside settlement to a major seaport on the Black Sea.\n\nVarna is an important centre for business, transportation, education, tourism, entertainment and healthcare. The city is referred to as the maritime capital of Bulgaria and headquarters the Bulgarian Navy and merchant marine. In 2008, Varna was designated seat of the Black Sea Euroregion by the Council of Europe. In 2014, Varna was awarded the title of European Youth Capital 2017.\n\nThe oldest gold treasure in the world, belonging to the Varna culture, was discovered in the Varna Necropolis and dates to 4200–4600 BC.\n\nCity landmarks include the Varna Archaeological Museum, exhibiting the Gold of Varna, the Roman Baths, the Battle of Varna Park Museum, the Naval Museum in the Italianate Villa Assareto displaying the museum ship Drazki torpedo boat, the Museum of Ethnography in an Ottoman-period compound featuring the life of local urban dwellers, fisherfolk, and peasants in the late 19th and early 20th century.\n\nThe \'Sea Garden\' is the oldest and perhaps largest park in town containing an open-air theatre (venue of the International Ballet Competition, opera performances and concerts), Varna Aquarium (opened 1932), the Festa Dolphinarium (opened 1984), the Nicolaus Copernicus Observatory and Planetarium, the Museum of Natural History, a terrarium, a zoo, an alpineum, a children\'s amusement park with a pond, boat house and ice-skating rink, and other attractions. The National Revival Alley is decorated with bronze monuments to prominent Bulgarians, and the Cosmonauts\' Alley contains trees planted by Yuri Gagarin and other Soviet and Bulgarian cosmonauts. The Garden is a national monument of landscape architecture and is said to be the largest landscaped park in the Balkans.</string>
    <string name="about_city_three">Burgas, sometimes transliterated as Bourgas, is the second largest city on the Bulgarian Black Sea Coast and the fourth-largest in Bulgaria after Sofia, Plovdiv, and Varna, with a population of 211,033 inhabitants, while 277,922 live in its urban area. It is the capital of Burgas Province and an important industrial, transport, cultural and tourist centre.\n\nThe city is surrounded by the Burgas Lakes and located at the westernmost point of the Black Sea, at the large Burgas Bay. The LUKOIL Neftochim Burgas is the largest oil refinery in southeastern Europe and the largest industrial enterprise. The Port of Burgas is the largest port in Bulgaria, and Burgas Airport is the second most important in the country. Burgas is the center of the Bulgarian fishing and fish processing industry.\n\nThe Burgas Wetlands are highly recognized for their significance to biodiversity and as a resource pool for products used by people.\n\nLake Burgas is Bulgaria\'s largest lake and is in the middle of the city. It is important for migrating birds. Over 250 species of birds inhabit the lake area, 61 of which are endangered in Bulgaria and 9 globally, attracting keen birdwatchers from all over the world. The lakes are also home to important fish and invertebrates. In the site have been recorded several IUCN Red-Listed species of animals — 5 invertebrates, 4 fish, 4 amphibians, 3 reptiles, 5 birds and 3 mammals. Situated along the second largest migration path of birds in Europe, the Via Pontica, the site is an important stopover and staging site for a large number of water-birds, raptors and passerines. Yearly during migration and wintering more than 20,000 (up to 100,000) waterbirds congregate there.\n\nThe Atanasovo Lake is one of two salt-water lakes in the Black Sea region and contains rare and representative examples of wetland habitats. It is a hot spot for biodiversity, with many Red-Listed species of plants and animals. It is a well-known bottleneck site for migratory birds, with around 60,000 raptors and 240,000 storks, pelicans and cranes passing over the site and often landing in large numbers for staging. The highest numbers in Europe of migrating White Pelicans (Pelecanus onocrotalus), Dalmatian Pelicans (Pelecanus crispus), Marsh Harriers (Circus aeruginosus) and Red-footed Falcons (Falco vespertinus) have been recorded here.</string>
    <string name="about_city_four">Plovdiv is the second-largest city in Bulgaria, and one of the oldest cities in Europe. It is located in the large plain between the Rhodope Mountains in the south of Bulgaria and the Balkan Range, or Old Mountains (Stara Planina) that runs through the center of Bulgaria. Both ranges are visible on clear days. The Maritsa River flows through the city on its way southeast before forming the Greek/Turkey border to the Aegean Sea.\n\nPlovdiv is the oldest continuously-inhabited city in Europe, which is now located on six hills. The first Thracian settlement on Nebet hill has been dated back to 6, 000 BC. The firts inhabitors of the city are suppost to have been thracian tribes - bessi and odrisi. In 342 BC Philip of Macedon conquered the city and gave it the name Philippopolis (\"Philippos\" and \"polis\" - city). In 12 AD the Romans started conquering the Thracian provinces on the territory which is nowadays Bulgaria. After the death of the thracian king Remetalk in 46 AD, Thracia was officially proclaimed a Roman province. During this period the city of Plovdiv was an important administrative center and soon afterwards it was proclaimed a Metropolitan city of the province Thracia. The city was called Trimontium (a city on three hills) but soon it regained its previous name Philippopolis.\n\nDuring the long occupation by the Ottoman Empire, a large mosque was built, still present in the centre area as well. During Communist times, a statue of the unnamed Russian soldier was erected on one of the three main hills which overlooks the city.\n\nToday, Plovdiv is a famous tourist destination itself and also serves as a gateway to many other points of interest. Plovdiv is well-known for hosting the Plovdiv International Fair twice a year and for its ancient sites.\n\nThe old Plovdiv is compact and walkable, with the main downtown road blocked to car traffic. There is a good collection of Bulgarian revival buildings in use as museums, hotels, and restaurants etc. and is worth a visit if you have chance. The nearby Roman Theatre, discovered in the 1970\'s during a construction project, is part of the pedestrian zone, and typically has merchants selling art and other items nearby. Wander the cobblestone streets near the downtown to find the centuries old St. Marina church with a unique wooden tower, a mosque from the Ottoman Empire, and on the nearby hill the old town center. The old town center was walled, and has a famous gateway entrance. Nearby Puldin Restaurant has subterranean rooms where the old wall and historic artifacts can be seen. Continuing up the hill several older houses are now museums and the Roman amphitheater with an overlook of the town below is partially restored and still used for concerts and other occasions.\n\nIn the new center of the city (at the street heading up into the old town) you will find the Roman stadium which dates back to the late 1st/early 2nd century. It had a capacity of 30,000 people; and as the Roman laws dictate that the city stadium should have seating for at least half the population, it summarily shows the town had 60,000 inhabitants during Roman times. In addition, the ancient theatre is capable of seating 6,000 people at once-again, Roman laws dictated that the theatres should accommodate one-tenth of the population at a time.\n\nWhen you go to the other end of the predestrian street, next to the Tourist Information Center and the post office, you will see the Roman Odeon and Forum. The forum was to Romans the downtown of today. This one had three sides of 13 shops on each side, and a fourth one for the bank, library, and other institutions of this sort.</string>
    <string name="about_app">This is not a commercial application. The video used in the application is owned by http://bulgariatravel.org/ and is here only for educational purposes!\n\nAuthor: Nikolai Berov\nUdacity Android Basics by Google Nanodegree Program\n2018</string>

    <string name="close">Close</string>

    <string name="cities">Cities</string>
    <string name="national_theater_description">The “Ivan Vazov” National Theatre is Bulgaria’s biggest theatre, as well as the oldest and most stand out and most imposing theatre in the country. This theatre is one of the major landmarks in Sofia due to its prime location and grandiose architecture.\n\nThe National theatre is located in the centre of Sofia and its edifice faces the City Garden. The Ivan Vazov National Theatre has a well-equipped main stage with 750 seats, a smaller 120-seat stage and an additional 70-seat one on the fourth floor. The theatre employs some of the country’s best actors and stage directors, many of whom are widely popular.\n\nFounded in 1904 by the artists from the “Salza i Smyah” theatre, initially, it was called simply the National Theatre, but soon after it was named after the prominent Bulgarian writer Ivan Vazov. The theatre’s Neoclassical building, designed by famous Viennese theatre architects Hermann Helmer and Ferdinand Fellner, was finished in 1906 and opened in 1907. A theatrical school was established as part of the National Theatre in 1925.\n\nA fire in 1923 and the bobmings in the World Was II seriously damaged the building, so the theater had a few reconstructions during the time. The number of seats in the main hall was increased, the scene was more spacious and modern equipment was provided. Virtually the original appearence of the theater was preserved, however, changes were made in the volume, interior and facade.</string>
    <string name="national_theater">\"Ivan Vazov\" National Theater</string>
    <string name="country">Bulgaria</string>
    <string name="sofia_theater_description">Today "Sofia" Theatre has a compact acting troupe with prominent artists from different generations, and has attracted several energetic and talented young artists, which has enhanced the practice of different particular shows. Invites many guests, which makes conditions for creative competition.\n\nOur goal is to preserve the theatrical traditions and at the same time to give way to the newest and most modern in contemporary theater. Each season the theater supports a repertoire of 10-12 titles that are been shown on four stages. Over the years, more than 550 titles of Bulgarian and foreign authors were placed at "Sofia" Theatre. Among the directors we can distinguish names like Benno Besson, Jed Allen Harris, Ruben Simonov and the doyens of Bulgarian theater - Leon Daniel, Vili Tsankov, Krasimir Spasov, Krikor Azaryan, NikolayPolyakov, Ivan Dobchev and many others.\n\nFor years "Sofia” Theatre is expanding the range of genres and annually includes one musical in its repertoire. It started years ago with”Hair” by Jerome Ragna and James Rado, "Love boulevards” from Stephan Tsanev and Yuri Stupel, and today we have in the repertoire “Jump” from Zdrava Kamenova and Martin Karov and "Peter Pan" by P. Ch. Robinson. "Sofia" Theatre has been a guest of prestigious European festivals and theatrical centers – “Evpolaiya” Antwerp, Belgium, International Festival "Dialogue", Wroclaw, Poland, International festival “Divadelna Nitra”, Slovakia, 12 International Youth Festival in Moscow Russia, International Dutch festival, at 83’s has been in The Hague, Netherlands, in Caen and Nancy, France, Budapest, Vienna, Austria and a ten-day tour in Cyprus in 1985.\n\nBesides its own production "Sofia" Theatre offers the viewers the opportunity to meet with the most interesting theater practice  in the country and abroad, being a host of the shortlisted for national award IKAR( the Union of Artists in Bulgaria awards annually distinguish artists) , also hosts the "World Theatre in Sofia" in partnership with the ITF "Varna Summer". Last season "Sofia" Theatre hosted the "Odeon\" Theatrefrom Bucharest- they  presented to the Bulgarian public two of their productions, winning prestigious theater awards at many festivals.\n\nIn partnership with the “Goethe Institute- Sofia”  "Sofia" Theatre organized "Open Day meeting with the art of Bertolt Brecht."\n\nThere areforthcoming initiatives with the British Council in Sofia, The French Cultural Institute and the Polish Cultural Institute. "Sofia" Theatre presented its productions in London, Berlin, Bratislava, Vienna, visiting the Bulgarian cultural institutes there. "Sofia" Theatre is always invited to present their productions of major theater festivals in the country, has won prestigious national awards “Icarus” and “Asker” and a awards from the Ministry of Culture and Sofia Municipality.</string>
    <string name="sofia_theater">\"Sofia\" Theatre</string>
    <string name="sofia_opera">Sofia Opera and Ballet</string>
    <string name="sofia_opera_description">50 years have passed since that particular autumn day in 1953 when in Sofia was officially opened the new National Opera, comfortably sheltered into the friendly arms of the Monumental House of BZNS [The Agrarian Union of Bulgaria], named “Alexander Stambolijsky”after the name of its popular leader.\n\nSofia National Opera, founded in 1890, is the oldest and most prestigious Bulgarian opera theatre.\n\nThere are many singers, conductors and directors who have contributed the professional achievements of the Sofia National Opera. Some of the stars of world opera, such as Nicolai Ghiaurov, Ghena Dimitrova, Nicola Guselev, Anna Tomova-Sintova have made the first steps of their artistic careers on the Sofia stage.\n\nIf you are an opera fan you will like it here. The tickets cost up to 40 leva (20 EUR)</string>
    <string name="sofia_ndk">The National Palace of Culture</string>
    <string name="sofia_ndk_description">The National Palace of Culture - Congress Centre Sofia (NDK) is the largest multifunctional complex in Southeastern Europe.\n\nThe Palace was officially opened in 1981 to mark 1300 years since the founding of the Bulgarian state. It was designed to host a wide range of events such as international conventions, official meetings, conferences, symposia, discussion panels, exhibitions, festivals, concerts. The Palace is located in downtown Sofia and is surrounded by a park area.\n\nThe main building was designed by arch. Alexander Barov and his team of architects, and the design of the surrounding areas is the work of arch. Atanas Agura and team. The park area was designed by landscape architect Valentina Atanassova.\n\n\nFACTS and FIGURES\n\n- 123 000 sq m in area, it is an eight-storey building, with four panoramic terraces and three underground levels\n- 300 parking spaces + an additional 40 for VIP parking\n- Over 300 events per annum with one million guests take place here annually\n- It houses 80 monumental works of art located in the halls and the foyers\n- Bulgaria\'s most renowned concert venue for international artists\n- Producer of theater, concerts, exhibitions and the annual festivals Salon des Arts, Cinemania, New Year\'s Music Fest\n- Home of the National Book Centre, The Feather (Peroto) Literary Club, Azaryan Theater and DNK Contemporary Dance and Performance Space</string>
    <string name="sofia_street_art_tour_description">Sofia Graffiti Tour is the first and only tour dedicated to the street art culture and community of the Bulgarian capital, Sofia. We aim to provide you with information about the history of street art in Sofia and its development, familiarise you with prominent street artists, and show you different writing and drawing styles.\n\nDuring the tour, which takes place in central Sofia, you’ll pass historical sights and places that are significant to locals. With our guidance, you’ll be able to follow the social and political changes that shaped our city into what it is today.\n\nBy the end of the tour you’ll be able to recognise the styles of particular street artists. You’ll also have learnt a bunch about the city’s street art curiousities: nicknames of street artists, stunning walls, vocabulary, and codes of conduct.</string>
    <string name="sofia_street_art_tour">Private Street Art Tour of Sofia</string>
    <string name="sofia_live_club">Sofia Live Club</string>
    <string name="sofia_live_club_description">SOFIA LIVE CLUB is the biggest club for live music in Sofia, which fully meets the highest standards of the European and Global club scenes. The club opened its doors for all quality rhythm lovers in May 2009. It is situated in an iconic cultural place, namely in the Fountain Underpass of the National Palace of Culture - a historical location for the Sofia nightlife.\n\nSOFIA LIVE CLUB forms a community, consisting of not only Bulgarian musical talent, but also most guest stars from the European and Global musical scene. The club\'s ambition to attract world class performers for concerts in front of the national public has already become a reality and quickly made the club a favorite place for music lovers. The club\'s stage is intended for both solo performances and concerts with a big band. It has an 8 meter LED video wall, video projector and screen. The technical, sound and lighting equipment meet the highest world standards.\n\nThe club has 270 seats and room for 630 standing guests, 3 dressing rooms, a royal, drum set and everything necessary for the successful performance of the artists. The goal of the club\'s founders is already accomplished, namely to turn the club into the most impressive stage for live music in the country. At night we can listen to jazz, pop, rock, alternative music, world music with a highlight on author projects. A genuinely revolutionary stage for live concerts!</string>
    <string name="sofia_zoo">Sofia Zoo</string>
    <string name="sofia_zoo_description">Sofia Zoo in Sofia, the capital of Bulgaria, was founded by royal decree on 1 May 1888, and is the oldest and largest zoological garden in southeastern Europe. It covers 36 hectares (89 acres) and, in March 2006, housed 4,850 animals representing 840 species.\n\nInitially, the zoo was located in the park of the former royal palace, with the primary attraction being a Eurasian black vulture caught in Bulgaria and exhibited in a cage in the garden. Later, pheasants and deer were added to the collection, but since the exhibits and facilities of the time proved inadequate to accommodate a pair of brown bears, Tsar Ferdinand of Bulgaria ordered a grant of land to be awarded to Sofia Zoo on the grounds of the former botanical garden, then in the outskirts of the city.\n\nSofia Zoo\'s exhibition of animals constantly increased, with both local and foreign species being added, most notably a pair of lions in 1892, which were housed in a former stable and a lion cub was born the same year.\n\nBetween 1893 and 1895, new cages and buildings were constructed to accommodate the ever-increasing collection of birds and mammals, including a solid three-room stone building in the back of the terrain designed to be inhabited by bears (1894), a pool where a few pink-backed pelicans lived, a building to accommodate pheasants and another one for eagles (1895).\n\nSofia Zoo moved from its original (and smaller) location in the centre of the city to a new 36-hectare (89-acre) site about 4.5 kilometres (2.8 mi) south of Sofia in 1982.</string>
    <string name="sofia_al_nevski">Alexander Nevsky Cathedral</string>
    <string name="sofia_al_nevski_description">The St. Alexander Nevsky Cathedral is a Bulgarian Orthodox cathedral in Sofia, the capital of Bulgaria. Built in Neo-Byzantine style, it serves as the cathedral church of the Patriarch of Bulgaria and it is one of the largest Eastern Orthodox cathedrals in the world, as well as one of Sofia\'s symbols and primary tourist attractions. The St. Alexander Nevsky Cathedral in Sofia occupies an area of 3,170 square metres (34,100 sq ft) and can hold 10,000 people inside. It is the second-largest cathedral located on the Balkan Peninsula, after the Cathedral of Saint Sava in Belgrade.\n\nThe Alexander Nevsky Cathedral is a cross-domed basilica featuring an emphasized central dome. The cathedral\'s gold-plated dome is 45 m high (148 ft), with the bell tower reaching 53 metres (174 ft). The temple has 12 bells with total weight of 23 tons, the heaviest weighing 12 tons and the lightest 10 kilograms (22 lb). The interior is decorated with Italian marble in various colours, Brazilian onyx, alabaster, and other luxurious materials. The central dome has the Lord\'s Prayer inscribed around it, with thin gold letters.\n\nThe construction of the St. Alexander Nevsky Cathedral started in 1882 (having been planned since 19 February, 1879), when the foundation stone was laid, but most of it was built between 1904 and 1912. Saint Alexander Nevsky was a Russian prince. The cathedral was created in honour to the Russian soldiers who died during the Russo-Turkish War of 1877-1878, as a result of which Bulgaria was liberated from Ottoman rule.\n\nThe cathedral was designed by Alexander Pomerantsev, aided by Alexander Smirnov and Alexander Yakovlev, as the initial 1884-1885 project of Ivan Bogomolov was radically changed by Pomerantsev. The final design was finished in 1898, and the construction and decoration were done by a team of Bulgarian, Russian, Austro-Hungarian and other European artists, architects and workers, including the aforementioned architects, as well as Petko Momchilov, Yordan Milanov, Haralampi Tachev, Ivan Mrkvička, Vasily Bolotnov, Nikolay Bruni, Alexander Kiselyov, Anton Mitov and many others.\n\nThe marble parts and the lighting fixtures were created in Munich, the metal elements for the gates in Berlin, while the gates themselves were manufactured in Karl Bamberg\'s factory in Vienna, and the mosaics were shipped from Venice.</string>
    <string name="sofia_nhm">National Historical Museum</string>
    <string name="sofia_nhm_description">The National Historical Museum in Sofia is Bulgaria\'s largest museum. It was founded on 5 May 1973. A new representative exhibition was opened in the building of the Court of Justice on 2 March 1984, to commemorate the 13th centenary of the Bulgarian state.\n\nThe museum was moved in 2000 to the former primary residence of the dictator and last communist leader Todor Zhivkov at Boyana, and currently contains over 650,000 objects connected to archaeology, fine arts, history and ethnography, although only 10% of them are permanently exhibited.\n\nThe museum includes a cloakroom, cafe, library and souvenir shop. It undertakes professional conservation and restoration of historical monuments, authenticity investigations and expert valuation. Its collections comprise materials dating from prehistoric ages till the present. As of 2016, the museum\'s director is Dr. Bozhidar Dimitrov, a historian.\n\nThe museum holds over 700,000 cultural monuments inside and tells the story of Bulgarian history dating back to the 7th century.</string>
    <string name="sofia_rotunda">St. George Rotunda</string>
    <string name="sofia_rotunda_description">The Church of St George is an Early Christian red brick rotunda that is considered the oldest building in Sofia, the capital of Bulgaria. It is situated behind the Sheraton Hotel, amid remains of the ancient town of Serdica.\n\nBuilt by the Romans in the 4th century, it is a cylindrical domed structure built on a square base. It is believed that it was built on the site of a pagan temple, though the original purpose of the building was for public use. The building is famous for the 12th-, 13th- and 14th-century frescoes inside the central dome. Three layers of frescoes have been discovered, the earliest dating back to the 10th century. Magnificent frescoes of 22 prophets over 2 metres tall crown the dome. Painted over during the Ottoman period, when the building was used as a mosque, these frescoes were only uncovered and restored in the 20th century.\n\nThe church is part of a larger archaeological complex. Behind the apse, there are ancient ruins: a section of a Roman street with preserved drainage, foundations of a large basilica, probably a public building, and some smaller buildings. One of the buildings had been equipped with hypocaust and the tiles lifting the floor can be seen today. Experts define it as one of the most beautiful buildings in the so-called "Constantine district" of Serdika-Sredets, where the palace of Emperor Constantine the Great, and later of Sebastokrator Kaloyan were situated. Having survived the trials of time and having kept its appearance almost untouched, it is assumed that some of the most important meetings of the Serdica Ecumenical Council had taken place in the church.\n\nThe Rotunda is a part of a large complex of ancient buildings from the late 3rd and early 4th century. It was built of red bricks and has a complex symmetry. At the centre, there is a domed rotunda room with a circular plan on a square base with semicircular niches in the corners. Since the 4th century, it has been used for christening (baptising) ceremonies. The dome rises to 13.70 m from the floor. Through the centuries it had been used as a public, religious and even a representative building.</string>
    <string name="sofia_east_gate">East Gate of Serdica Ruins</string>
    <string name="sofia_east_gate_description">In the underpass between the Council of Ministers and the Presidency go downstairs and you will see the remains from the East Gate of Serdica. Here you will walk on original Roman street, covered by large stone plates.\n\nAccording to the archeologists the street was lastly repaired in the 6th century. The gate was defended by two triangular towers – one at each of its sides. From here one of the most important Roman roads – Via Diagonalis or Via Militaris continued south-eastwards to the city of Philippopolis (present-day Plovdiv). In the underpass you should see the plan of Roman Serdica, hanging on the wall against the remains of the gate. From it you can receive a better orientation what you have seen from the ancient city and what is remaining to see.\n\nIf you have free time to spend while you are in the city center of Sofia, we suggest you to make a pleasant and relaxed walk, exploring the archeological monuments left to remind us about the glorious past of the Bulgarian capital – a proud successor of the large and important antique Thracian and Roman city of Serdica.</string>
    <string name="sofia_roman_wall">Roman Wall Sofia</string>
    <string name="sofia_roman_wall_description">Roman wall in Sofia, also known as the old wall is not really Roman. It is a Ottoman construction. It is believed that it was built in the first centuries of Ottoman rule. It forms part of a small square building, whose purpose has several theories.\n\nFor the most reasonable assumption is believed that this is a tomb of a prominent Turkish building erected within the Turkish cemeteries, which were present before the liberation of the region. According to other information it is a “part of” namazgyaf “- where he served imam prayer for those who go for pilgrimage. End walls were lined large stones on which prospective pilgrims foot to get on their horses.”\n\nPreserved wall is built with the typical Ottoman cell construction – stone in a rectangular box of bricks. In the wall there are two high Window openings, and between them, facing west, was built niche. At the top of the wall is a toothed cornice of brick.</string>
    <string name="varna_roman_baths">Roman Baths</string>
    <string name="varna_roman_baths_description">Covering a surface of 7,500 square meters, the Roman Baths in Varna are the third largest ancient Roman baths in Europe, outsized by those of Diocletian and Caracalla in Rome and the ones in Trier, Germany. Varna’s bath complex was built sometime during the 2nd century A.D., when Varna was known as Odessos. The baths were not only for bathing, but also for important business meetings and socializing. Today, the Roman baths of Varna are in ruins, but visitors still have a chance to walk through the different rooms (frigidarium, tepidarium, caldarium, and sports complex).</string>
    <string name="varna_opera_theatre">Varna Opera Theatre</string>
    <string name="varna_opera_theatre_description">The Varna Opera is an opera house in Varna, Bulgaria. It is part of the Opera and Philharmonic Society of Varna, founded by a merger of the Opera House and Philharmonic Society in 1999. The theatre itself originally opened in 1947.\n\nThe history of the theatre, currently known as the Varna Opera Theater, dates back to 1912 when the foundation was laid for the theatre. Its creation was temporarily delayed due to the coming Balkan Wars. After the wars ended, the theatre was inaugurated in 1932. It was registered under the title of the Varna Public Opera House on April 6, 1947 and was officially opened on August 1 of the same year. Stefan Nikolaev was appointed as the theatre\'s first director and Peter Raichev, a distinguished Bulgarian singer, was invited to be the first art director.\n\nAn orchestra, a choir and a ballet group were formed under the leadership of the young conductor Raichev, the choir-master Dimiter Mladenov and the choreographer Assen Manolov. Aside from the theatre\'s usual participation in opera productions and children\'s music shows, the corps de ballet stages ballet productions. The Varna Opera Corps de ballet has had many tours in Greece, India, Egypt, Germany, Austria, Switzerland and Romania.</string>
    <string name="varna_dolphinarium">Dolphinarium Varna</string>
    <string name="varna_dolphinarium_description">Festa Dolphinarium is the only attraction of its kind in Bulgaria. It is situated amidst the greenery of the Seaside Garden of Varna and offers a wonderful view over the sea.\n\nThe Dolphinarium was inaugurated on 11.08.1984 and quickly became a symbol of Varna and a landmark of Bulgarian tourism. The Dolphinarium is a permanent site on the agenda of all visitors of the Black Sea coast.\n\nThe building impresses with its futuristic structure and glass-and-aluminum front wall. The Dolphinarium building was designed by a team led by renowned architect Simeon Saraliev. The building itself is a light spatial structure shaped as a glass cube of walls 30 meters long and 14 meters high. Interesting is the fact that the earthworks at installation floor and pools were done after the bearing roof structure had been mounted.</string>
    <string name="varna_bar_cubo">Cubo Bar</string>
    <string name="varna_bar_cubo_description">Why locals love it\nCubo is probably the best known beach bar in Varna. It is loved and mostly visited by the alternative and bohemian people but in the recent years it became so popular that you can already find there every kind of person.\n\nWhy you should visit it\nIt is a very popular bar but not a "tourist trap" because Varna is not a major destination and the most people who visit it are still the locals.Visit Cubo and you will enjoy cocktails, some funky music and the sound of the waves in the hot summer nights.\n\nSpecial tip\nTry the typical bulgarian cocktail "Mint Liquor with Sprite" but drink responsibly since it is fairly sweet and can easily swipe you off your feet.</string>


</resources>
